Oliver Bada



badaoliver7@gmail.com



linkedin.com/in/oliverbada



+254706984404



https://github.com/OliverBada

Summary

A graduate in BA History and International Studies with over 3 years experience in community building and project management, with a stellar track record in capacity building, coaching and training and great communication skills. As an ALX-certified Virtual Assistant I am experienced in working in multi-cultural teams while focusing on project deliverable deadlines and work plans leadership positions.

Currently, I am enrolled in the ALX Software Engineering program and also the CS50's Web Programming with Python and JavaScript building my software development skills focusing on HTML5, CSS3 ,JavaScript, Python and C, GitHub and Unix programming.

Experience



Executive Director

Youth for Sustainable Development - Taita Taveta Chapter

Aug 2021 - Present (1 year 6 months)

Youth-led and youth-serving organization promoting sustainable and inclusive engagement of youth and marginalized communities in socio-economic spheres under health, education and livelihoods especially PWDs and PLHIV.

- Manage a team of approximately 35 youths in implementing community development projects.
- Develop executable work plans on community engagement working with a budget over Ksh.300,000.
- Plan and execute trainings and mentorship programs ranging from SRH, financial literacy, and food security to mental health targeting youth, PWDs and PLHIV.
- Spearheaded the establishment of strong partnerships and linkages with several stakeholders e.g. County Government, W.H.O, Sauti ya Wanawake etc.
- Spearheaded the development/drafting of the Taita Taveta County Youth Policy pending public participation.
- Supported the Taita Taveta County Sexual Gender Based Violence Technical Working Group in training relevant power holders on how to use the county's GBV Tool.
- Organize a Social Accountability program to hold service providers accountable on provision of youth friendly services under sexual reproductive health through political economy analysis and a community scorecard.
- Collaborated with the Taita Taveta County Health department in carrying out over 5 community forums on sexual reproductive health targeting the youth and PWDs.

vso Project Lead, Food Systems/Climate Adaptation Project

VSO

Feb 2021 - Present (2 years)

As part of the United Nations efforts to end world hunger and promote nutrition across the world, this project aimed to get the voices of the youth when it comes to food systems in line with the UN Summit of 2021 termed Transformed Food Systems.

- Developed a work plan and identified Primary actors and potential stake holders to engage
- Mobilized the public through social media and inform them on the upcoming food summit.

- Reviewed existing VSO documents such as the Vulnerability assessments, score cards, PAR reports
 and other external documents of that area to develop a broad context analysis of key issues in food
 systems within the counties.
- Conducted round table dialogues with stakeholders and primary actors.
- Managed to conduct capacity building trainings on food systems primary actors on resilience in agricultural farming, creating awareness on youth in agribusiness and following up with stakeholders on commitments made from the food systems dialogue

vso Project Lead, COVID-19 Input Tracking Data Tool Project (ITDT)

VSO

Dec 2020 - Present (2 years 2 months)

Risk Communication and Community Engagement initiative in response to the COVID-19 pandemic in collaboration with the World Health Organization.

- Trained Community Health Volunteers on administration of Continuation of Essential Services (CES) and Infection Prevention Control (IPC) tools
- Managed a team of over 10 youths in successful administration of the two tools.
- Successfully conducted Volunteer action at home. This is where volunteers identify a community which has at least 1000 people busy operating in the area in a day and cause change in human behavior in regards to adhering to COVID-19 rules.
- Formed meaningful partnerships and I was able to help the County government of Taita Taveta to take up the two tools and integrate them into their systems in regards to fighting COVID-19.
- Reached over 300 people to get the community feedback and used this information to influence their behavior and at the same time report the same to the county government and also the World Health Organization.
- Oversaw the training of 5 Community Health Volunteers (CHVs) and led them in conducting field research and compiling the final report while also handling the financial side to disburse their allowances.
- Collaborated with the Ministry of Health to review the National Communication Community Engagement Strategy formulated due to the COVID-19 pandemic.

vso ICS Team Leader

VSO

Oct 2020 - Dec 2020 (3 months)

A global volunteering program aimed at young people working in projects that combat poverty.

- Managed a team of 7 volunteers to deliver development projects centered on building resilient livelihoods and health.
- Managed to advocate for the rights of PWDs in Taita Taveta by organizing a meeting for them to air out their views then presenting the same to the service providers, county government and stakeholders to implement the document.
- Managed to reach over 15 youth and women groups and conducting trainings for them in financial literacy, entrepreneurship and also linking them with potential partners
- Successfully saw through the pilot stage of launching two Input Tracking Data Tools in response to the COVID-19 pandemic. These tools helped the national and county government in monitoring perceptions, risk behavior and scores when it comes to adhering to the COVID-19 regulations.

Correspondent with World Atlas

Worldatlas.com

Feb 2018 - May 2018 (4 months)

A geographical website that extends to other topics like sociology, environment, economics, politics and travel among others. Duties included: research and writing articles.

Managed to research and write over 30 articles published on the website.

Education



🤛 alx_africa

Full Stack Software Engineering Program

Jun 2022 - Jul 2023

Certification in:

C Programming

Graphic Programming

Unix Programming

Data Structure & Algorithms

Reverse Engineering & Security

Python

Front-end dev

Linux/command line

Infrastructure Design & Management

Egerton University

Bachelor of Arts (B.A.), History and International Studies 2014 - 2018

Kenyatta High School

The Kenya Certificate of Secondary Education (KCSE)

2010 - 2013

Student leader for one year

Licenses & Certifications



Fundamentals of Software Testing - QATestLab



ALX Virtual Assistant Course_Honors - alx_africa

cer-a382ca3f-2ec2-4e6e-b72a-cbb96275

Skills

Project Implementation • Article Writing • JavaScript • Python (Programming Language) • HTML5 Cascading Style Sheets (CSS)
 Coaching & Mentoring
 Leadership
 Manual Testing Communication